{"componentChunkName":"component---src-templates-establishment-page-js","path":"/establishment/2140","result":{"data":{"site":{"pathPrefix":"/restaurant-inspections"},"postgres":{"establishment":[{"establishmentid":"2140","name":"Honest John's Bar & Grill","address":"488 Selden St.","zipcode":"48201","owner":"John Kwiatkowski","licenseNumber":"040399","licenseType":"Fixed Establishment","establishmentType":"Food Service Establishment","establishmentStatus":"Open","riskCategory":"High","reviewFrequencyDays":"150","coords":"-83.06395,42.34779","geojson":{"id":"2140","type":"Feature","geometry":{"type":"Point","coordinates":[-83.063954498,42.347791189]},"properties":{"name":"Honest John's Bar & Grill","owner":"John Kwiatkowski","address":"488 Selden St.","zipcode":"48201","license_type":"Fixed Establishment","risk_category":"High","license_number":"040399","establishmentid":"2140","establishment_type":"Food Service Establishment","establishment_status":"Open","review_frequency_days":"150","most_recent_license_date":"5/4/2022"}},"nearbyList":[{"establishmentid":"51623815","name":"Ice Cream Detroit","address":"3762 2nd St.","zipcode":"48207"},{"establishmentid":"51622663","name":"SheWolf Pastificio & Bar","address":"438 Selden St.","zipcode":"48201"},{"establishmentid":"4827","name":"Selden Standard","address":"3921-29  Second Ave.","zipcode":"48201"},{"establishmentid":"5372","name":"Foundation Rock Spirits LLC dba Castalia","address":"3980 Second Ave.","zipcode":"48201"},{"establishmentid":"51623656","name":"Foundation Rock Spirits-Stadt Garten","address":"3980 Second Ave","zipcode":"48201"},{"establishmentid":"237","name":"Cass Community UMC & Center","address":"3901 Cass Ave.","zipcode":"48201"},{"establishmentid":"51622936","name":"Smith & Co. ","address":"644 Selden St.","zipcode":"48201"},{"establishmentid":"4152","name":"Slows To Go","address":"4107 Cass Ave.","zipcode":"48201"},{"establishmentid":"5042","name":"Slows On The Go Mobile Kitchen","address":"4107 Cass Ave.","zipcode":"48201"},{"establishmentid":"51624017","name":"Slows To Go Food Truck ","address":"4107 Cass Ave ","zipcode":"48201"}],"inspectionsByEstablishmentidList":[{"inspectionid":"61604","inspectionDate":"2023-02-16T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"No","violationsByInspectionidList":[]},{"inspectionid":"60410","inspectionDate":"2022-09-23T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Complaint","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[]},{"inspectionid":"55533","inspectionDate":"2021-08-10T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"No","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"violationCode":"MFL289.6125","violationDescription":"Ice bins and machines;  connection with waste line.*  Sec. 6125. The waste line from ice storage bins and ice machines shall not be  directly connected with another waste line and shall be drained through an air  gap.","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":null,"subItem":"","problemDescription":null,"subProblem":"","location":"BASEMENT","subLocation":"Ice machine","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"4-501.114","violationDescription":"A chemical SANITIZER used in a SANITIZING solution for a manual or\nmechanical operation shall meet these limits or as otherwise approved: (P)\n\tChlorine        ppm           pH<10             pH<8\n\t\t      25              120 F              120 F\n\t\t      50              100 F              75 F\n\t\t     100              55 F               55 F\n                 Iodine           a concentration of between 12.5 and 25 ppm and minimum temp of 75 F and pH of 5 or less or meets manufacturer's specifications. (P)\n\n                Quats            minimum temperature of 75 F, hardness of 500 ppm or less and meet manufacturers use directions. (P)\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Chlorine solution concentration","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Below 50 ppm","subProblem":"","location":"DISH MACHINE","subLocation":"SANITIZING","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Provide correct concentration as stated above."},{"violationCode":"4-302.14","violationDescription":"A test kit or other device that accurately measures the concentration in mg/L of SANITIZING solutions shall be provided. (Pf)\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Sanitizer test kit","subItem":"chlorine","problemDescription":"Not provided","subProblem":"","location":"DISH ROOM","subLocation":"Test strips","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Provide."},{"violationCode":"4-302.12","violationDescription":"(A) FOOD TEMPERATURE MEASURING DEVICES shall be provided and readily accessible for use in ensuring attainment and maintenance of FOOD temperatures as specified under Chapter 3. (Pf)   \n(B) A TEMPERATURE MEASURING DEVICE with a suitable small-diameter probe that is designed to measure the temperature of thin masses shall be provided and readily accessible to accurately measure the temperature in thin FOODS such as MEAT patties and FISH filets. (Pf)\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Food thermometer(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not available","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"Food thermometer(s)","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Make available at all times."},{"violationCode":"3-305.12","violationDescription":"FOOD may not be stored:\n(A)  In locker rooms;\n(B)  In toilet rooms;\n(C)  In dressing rooms;\n(D)  In garbage rooms;\n(E)  In mechanical rooms;\n(F)  Under sewer lines that are not shielded to intercept potential drips;\n(G)  Under leaking water lines, including leaking automatic fire sprinkler heads, or        under lines on which water has condensed;\n(H)  Under open stairwells; or\n(I)   Under other sources of contamination.\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Food(s) stored","subItem":"","problemDescription":"In prohibited area(s)","subProblem":"Under sewer line(s)","location":"BASEMENT","subLocation":"Food Storage","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Store in protected manner."},{"violationCode":"4-401.11","violationDescription":"EQUIPMENT, a cabinet used for the storage of FOOD, or a cabinet that is used to store cleaned and SANITIZED EQUIPMENT, UTENSILS, laundered LINENS, and SINGLE-SERVICE and SINGLE-USE ARTICLES may not be located in an unsuitable areas or where exposed to possible contamination.\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Equipment","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Stored","subProblem":"Under unshielded sewer lines","location":"BASEMENT","subLocation":"LINEN STORAGE","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Remove and store in protected area."},{"violationCode":"4-903.11","violationDescription":"Cleaned EQUIPMENT and UTENSILS, laundered LINENS, and SINGLE-SERVICE and SINGLE-USE ARTICLES shall be stored in an approved manner and location.\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Single-service/single-use article(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Stored on floor or less than 6 inches above floor","subProblem":"","location":"BASEMENT","subLocation":"Single service items","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Store at least 6 inches above the floor."},{"violationCode":"5-205.15","violationDescription":"A PLUMBING SYSTEM shall be:\n(A) Repaired according to LAW; (P) and\n(B) Maintained in good repair.\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Drainage system","subItem":"drain lines","problemDescription":null,"subProblem":"","location":"BASEMENT","subLocation":"Drain line","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"3-305.11","violationDescription":"FOOD shall be protected from contamination by storing the FOOD:\n(1)     In a clean, dry location;\n(2)     Where it is not exposed to splash, dust, or other contamination; and\n(3)     At least 15 cm (6 inches) above the floor, unless otherwise approved.\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Food item(s) in storage","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Stored on floor or less than 6 inches above floor","subProblem":"","location":"BASEMENT","subLocation":"Food Storage","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Store at least 6 inches above the floor."},{"violationCode":"2-401.11","violationDescription":"(A)    An EMPLOYEE shall eat, drink, or use any form of tobacco only in designated areas where the contamination of exposed FOOD; clean EQUIPMENT, UTENSILS, and LINENS; unwrapped SINGLE-SERVICE and SINGLE-USE ARTICLES; or other items needing protection can not result.\n(B)     A FOOD EMPLOYEE may drink from a closed BEVERAGE container if the container is handled to prevent contamination of:\n         (1)     The EMPLOYEE'S hands;\n         (2)     The container; and\n         (3)     Exposed FOOD; clean EQUIPMENT, UTENSILS, and LINENS; and unwrapped SINGLE-SERVICE and SINGLE-USE ARTICLES.\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Beverage container","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Stored improperly","subProblem":"With exposed food","location":"BASEMENT","subLocation":"Personal items","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":"0001-01-01T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Air dry wiping cloths in manner that does not contaminate other items."}]},{"inspectionid":"55140","inspectionDate":"2021-06-21T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Complaint","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[]},{"inspectionid":"54600","inspectionDate":"2021-04-01T00:00:00","inspectionType":"COVID19 SITE CHECK","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[]},{"inspectionid":"54103","inspectionDate":"2020-11-24T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Outdoor cafe Eval","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[]},{"inspectionid":"51861","inspectionDate":"2020-06-15T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Outdoor cafe Eval","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[]},{"inspectionid":"51609","inspectionDate":"2020-03-23T00:00:00","inspectionType":"COVID19-temp closed","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[]},{"inspectionid":"50575","inspectionDate":"2020-01-22T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"violationCode":"7-201.11","violationDescription":"POISONOUS OR TOXIC MATERIAL shall be stored so they can not contaminate FOOD, EQUIPMENT, UTENSILS, LINENS, AND SINGLE-SERVICE AND SINGLE-USE ARTICLES by:   \n(A) Separating the POISONOUS OR TOXIC MATERIAL by spacing or partitioning; (P) and   \n(B) Locating the POISONOUS OR TOXIC MATERIAL in an area that is not above FOOD, EQUIPMENT, UTENSILS, LINENS, AND SINGLE-SERVICE AND SINGLE-USE ARTICLES.  This paragraph does not apply to EQUIPMENT and UTENSIL cleaners and sanitizers that are stored in WAREWASHING areas for availability and convenience if the materials are stored to prevent contamination of FOOD, EQUIPMENT, UTENSILS, LINENS, AND SINGLE-SERVICE and SINGLE-USE ARTICLES. (P)","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Poisonous/toxic material(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not separated from","subProblem":"Food","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"0001-01-01T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Provide adequate separation to prevent contamination."},{"violationCode":"3-302.11","violationDescription":"(A) FOOD shall be protected from cross contamination by:  \n(1) Except as specified in (1)(c) below, separating raw animal FOODS during         storage, preparation, holding, and display from:\n(a) Raw READY-TO-EAT FOOD including other raw animal FOOD such as FISH for sushi or MOLLUSCAN SHELLFISH, or other raw READY-TO-EAT FOOD such as fruits and vegetables,(P) and\n(b) Cooked READY-TO-EAT FOOD; (P)\n(c) Frozen, commercially processed and packaged raw animal FOOD may be          stored or displayed with or above frozen, commercially processed and           packaged, ready-to-eat food.\n(2) Except when combined as ingredients, separating types of raw animal FOODS    from each other such as beef, FISH, lamb, pork, and POULTRY during storage,        preparation, holding, and display by:\n(a) Using separate EQUIPMENT for each type, (P) or\n(b) Arranging each type of FOOD in EQUIPMENT so that cross contamination of one type with another is prevented, (P) and\n(c) Preparing each type of FOOD at different times or in separate areas; (P)\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Raw animal food(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Stored over/next to","subProblem":"Ready-to-eat food(s)","location":"COOLER","subLocation":"","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"0001-01-01T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Store raw animal foods below and away from foods needing little or no further prep."},{"violationCode":"4-602.11","violationDescription":"(A) Equipment FOOD-CONTACT SURFACES and UTENSILS shall be cleaned:     \n  (1) Except as specified in ¶ (B) of this section, before each use with a different   type of raw animal FOOD such as beef, FISH, lamb, pork, or POULTRY; (P)   \n  (2) Each time there is a change from working with raw FOODS to working with   READY-TO-EAT FOODS; (P)   \n  (3) Between uses with raw fruits and vegetables and with POTENTIALLY   HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD);   (P)   \n  (4) Before using or storing a FOOD TEMPERATURE MEASURING   DEVICE; (P) and   \n  (5) At any time during the operation when contamination may have occurred. (P)\n(B) Subparagraph (A)(1) of this section does not apply if the FOOD-CONTACT SURFACE or UTENSIL is in contact with a succession of different raw animal FOODS each requiring a higher cooking temperature as specified under § 3-401.11 than the previous FOOD, such as preparing raw FISH followed by cutting raw poultry on the same cutting board.   \n(C) Except as specified in ¶ (D) of this section, if used with POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD), EQUIPMENT FOOD-CONTACT SURFACES and UTENSILS shall be cleaned throughout the day at least every 4 hours. (P)   \n(D) Except when dry cleaning methods are used as specified under § 4-603.11, surfaces of UTENSILS and EQUIPMENT contacting FOOD that is not POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD) shall be cleaned:     \n  (1)   At any time when contamination may have occurred;\n  (2)   At least every 24 hours for iced tea dispensers and CONSUMER self-service UTENSILS such as tongs, scoops, or ladles;\n  (3) Before restocking CONSUMER self-service EQUIPMENT and UTENSILS such as condiment dispensers and display containers; and\n  (4) In EQUIPMENT such as ice bins and BEVERAGE dispensing nozzles and   enclosed components of EQUIPMENT such as ice makers, cooking oil storage   tanks and distribution lines, BEVERAGE and syrup dispensing lines or tubes,   coffee bean grinders, and water vending EQUIPMENT:\n     (a) At a frequency specified by the manufacturer, or\n     (b) Absent manufacturer specifications, at a frequency necessary to preclude      accumulation of soil or mold.","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Food-contact surface(s) used for nonpotentially hazardous food(s)","subItem":"ice bin(s)","problemDescription":"Not cleaned","subProblem":"","location":"BASEMENT STOREROOM","subLocation":"","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"0001-01-01T00:00:00","correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"7-102.11","violationDescription":"Working containers used for storing POISONOUS OR TOXIC MATERIALS such as cleaners and SANITIZERS taken from bulk supplies shall be clearly and individually identified with the common name of the material. (Pf)\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Working containers-toxics","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not labeled as to content","subProblem":"","location":"BAR(S)","subLocation":"","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"0001-01-01T00:00:00","correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"6-301.12","violationDescription":"Each HANDWASHING SINK or group of adjacent HANDWASHING SINKS shall be provided with:\n(A) Individual, disposable towels; (Pf)\n(B) A continuous towel system that supplies the user with a clean towel;(Pf) or \n(C) A heated-air hand drying device.(Pf)\n(D) A hand drying device that employs an air-knife system that delivers high velocity pressurized air at ambient temperatures.(Pf)\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Sanitary hand drying provisions","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not provided","subProblem":"At hand sink","location":"BAR(S)","subLocation":"","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"0001-01-01T00:00:00","correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"4-901.11","violationDescription":"After cleaning and SANITIZING, EQUIPMENT and UTENSILS shall be air-dried or used after adequate draining.\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Clean equipment and utensil(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Stored/stacked wet","subProblem":"","location":"DISHWASHING AREA","subLocation":"","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":"0001-01-01T00:00:00","correctionDescription":null}]},{"inspectionid":"48434","inspectionDate":"2019-07-12T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"No","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"violationCode":"4-602.11","violationDescription":"(A) Equipment FOOD-CONTACT SURFACES and UTENSILS shall be cleaned:     \n  (1) Except as specified in ¶ (B) of this section, before each use with a different   type of raw animal FOOD such as beef, FISH, lamb, pork, or POULTRY; (P)   \n  (2) Each time there is a change from working with raw FOODS to working with   READY-TO-EAT FOODS; (P)   \n  (3) Between uses with raw fruits and vegetables and with POTENTIALLY   HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD);   (P)   \n  (4) Before using or storing a FOOD TEMPERATURE MEASURING   DEVICE; (P) and   \n  (5) At any time during the operation when contamination may have occurred. (P)\n(B) Subparagraph (A)(1) of this section does not apply if the FOOD-CONTACT SURFACE or UTENSIL is in contact with a succession of different raw animal FOODS each requiring a higher cooking temperature as specified under § 3-401.11 than the previous FOOD, such as preparing raw FISH followed by cutting raw poultry on the same cutting board.   \n(C) Except as specified in ¶ (D) of this section, if used with POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD), EQUIPMENT FOOD-CONTACT SURFACES and UTENSILS shall be cleaned throughout the day at least every 4 hours. (P)   \n(D) Except when dry cleaning methods are used as specified under § 4-603.11, surfaces of UTENSILS and EQUIPMENT contacting FOOD that is not POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD) shall be cleaned:     \n  (1)   At any time when contamination may have occurred;\n  (2)   At least every 24 hours for iced tea dispensers and CONSUMER self-service UTENSILS such as tongs, scoops, or ladles;\n  (3) Before restocking CONSUMER self-service EQUIPMENT and UTENSILS such as condiment dispensers and display containers; and\n  (4) In EQUIPMENT such as ice bins and BEVERAGE dispensing nozzles and   enclosed components of EQUIPMENT such as ice makers, cooking oil storage   tanks and distribution lines, BEVERAGE and syrup dispensing lines or tubes,   coffee bean grinders, and water vending EQUIPMENT:\n     (a) At a frequency specified by the manufacturer, or\n     (b) Absent manufacturer specifications, at a frequency necessary to preclude      accumulation of soil or mold.","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Food-contact surface(s) and utensil(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not cleaned","subProblem":"After any contamination","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"2-301.14","violationDescription":"FOOD EMPLOYEES shall clean their hands and exposed portions of their arms as specified under § 2-301.12 immediately before engaging in FOOD preparation including working with exposed FOOD, clean EQUIPMENT and UTENSILS, and unwrapped SINGLE-SERVICE and SINGLE-USE ARTICLES (P) and:\n(A)     After touching bare human body parts other than clean hands and clean, exposed portions of arms; (P)\n(B)     After using the toilet room; (P)\n(C)     After caring for or handling SERVICE ANIMALS or aquatic animals as specified in ¶ 2-403.11(B); (P).\n(D)     Except as specified in ¶ 2-401.11(B), after coughing, sneezing, using a handkerchief or disposable tissue, using tobacco, eating, or drinking; (P)\n(E)     After handling soiled EQUIPMENT or UTENSILS; (P)\n(F)     During FOOD preparation, as often as necessary to remove soil and contamination and to prevent cross contamination when changing tasks; (P)\n(G)     When switching between working with raw FOOD and working with READY-TO-EAT FOOD; (P)\n(H)     Before donning gloves for working with FOOD; (P) and\n(I)      After engaging in other activities that contaminate the hands. (P)","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Employee(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Did not wash hands","subProblem":"after handling soiled equipment, surfaces, utensils","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"DISHWASHING AREA","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"3-501.17","violationDescription":"(A)  READY-TO-EAT, POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD)  prepared and held refrigerated for more than 24 hours in a FOOD ESTABLISHMENT  shall be clearly marked at the time of preparation to indicate the date or day by which the FOOD shall be consumed. (Pf)\n(B)  A container of refrigerated, commercially prepared READY-TO-EAT POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD)  shall be clearly marked, at the time the original container is opened in a FOOD ESTABLISHMENT, to indicate the date or day by which the FOOD shall be consumed. (Pf)\n\nA date marking system that does not exceed 7 days, including date of preparation, or opening is to be used. (Pf)\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"In house prepared ready-to-eat potentially hazardous  food(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Improperly date marked","subProblem":"Longer than 7 days stored at 41 degrees f","location":"BASEMENT","subLocation":"WALK-IN COOLER","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"0001-01-01T00:00:00","correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"2-103.11","violationDescription":"The PERSON IN CHARGE shall ensure that employees, practices and policies are in compliance with the code. (Pf) \n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Person-in-charge","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not ensuring compliance","subProblem":"","location":"PERSON IN CHARGE","subLocation":"","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"0001-01-01T00:00:00","correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"4-602.11","violationDescription":"(A) Equipment FOOD-CONTACT SURFACES and UTENSILS shall be cleaned:     \n  (1) Except as specified in ¶ (B) of this section, before each use with a different   type of raw animal FOOD such as beef, FISH, lamb, pork, or POULTRY; (P)   \n  (2) Each time there is a change from working with raw FOODS to working with   READY-TO-EAT FOODS; (P)   \n  (3) Between uses with raw fruits and vegetables and with POTENTIALLY   HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD);   (P)   \n  (4) Before using or storing a FOOD TEMPERATURE MEASURING   DEVICE; (P) and   \n  (5) At any time during the operation when contamination may have occurred. (P)\n(B) Subparagraph (A)(1) of this section does not apply if the FOOD-CONTACT SURFACE or UTENSIL is in contact with a succession of different raw animal FOODS each requiring a higher cooking temperature as specified under § 3-401.11 than the previous FOOD, such as preparing raw FISH followed by cutting raw poultry on the same cutting board.   \n(C) Except as specified in ¶ (D) of this section, if used with POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD), EQUIPMENT FOOD-CONTACT SURFACES and UTENSILS shall be cleaned throughout the day at least every 4 hours. (P)   \n(D) Except when dry cleaning methods are used as specified under § 4-603.11, surfaces of UTENSILS and EQUIPMENT contacting FOOD that is not POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD) shall be cleaned:     \n  (1)   At any time when contamination may have occurred;\n  (2)   At least every 24 hours for iced tea dispensers and CONSUMER self-service UTENSILS such as tongs, scoops, or ladles;\n  (3) Before restocking CONSUMER self-service EQUIPMENT and UTENSILS such as condiment dispensers and display containers; and\n  (4) In EQUIPMENT such as ice bins and BEVERAGE dispensing nozzles and   enclosed components of EQUIPMENT such as ice makers, cooking oil storage   tanks and distribution lines, BEVERAGE and syrup dispensing lines or tubes,   coffee bean grinders, and water vending EQUIPMENT:\n     (a) At a frequency specified by the manufacturer, or\n     (b) Absent manufacturer specifications, at a frequency necessary to preclude      accumulation of soil or mold.","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Food-contact surface(s) used for nonpotentially hazardous food(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not cleaned","subProblem":"At least every 24 hours","location":"BAR","subLocation":"BEVERAGE GUN HOLSTER","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"4-501.11","violationDescription":"EQUIPMENT shall be maintained in a state of repair and condition that meets the requirements of the code.\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Equipment","subItem":"","problemDescription":"In poor repair","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"Hand sink(s)","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"4-602.12","violationDescription":"(A) The FOOD-CONTACT SURFACES of cooking and baking EQUIPMENT shall be cleaned at least every 24 hours. This section does not apply to hot oil cooking and filtering EQUIPMENT if it is cleaned as specified in Subparagraph 4-602.11(D)(6).   \n(B) The cavities and door seals of microwave ovens shall be cleaned at least every 24 hours by using the manufacturer's recommended cleaning procedure.","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Baking and cooking equipment","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not cleaned","subProblem":"At least every 24 hours","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"Cooking equipment","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Clean as specified above."},{"violationCode":"4-501.14","violationDescription":"A WAREWASHING machine; the compartments of sinks, basins, or  other receptacles used for washing and rinsing EQUIPMENT, UTENSILS, or raw FOODS, or laundering wiping cloths; and drainboards or other EQUIPMENT used to substitute for drainboards shall be cleaned as required.\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Warewashing equipment","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not cleaned","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"6-501.12","violationDescription":"(A) PHYSICAL FACILITIES shall be cleaned as often as necessary to keep them clean.\n(B) Except spill cleanup, cleaning shall be done during periods when the least amount of FOOD is exposed such as after closing. ","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Physical facilities/structures","subItem":"","problemDescription":"With accumulation of debris","subProblem":"","location":"FACILITY","subLocation":"Throughout","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Keep clean."},{"violationCode":"2-402.11","violationDescription":"FOOD EMPLOYEES shall wear hair restraints such as hats, hair coverings or nets, beard restraints, and clothing that covers body hair, that are designed and worn to effectively keep their hair from contacting exposed FOOD; clean EQUIPMENT, UTENSILS, and LINENS; or unwrapped SINGLE-SERVICE or SINGLE-USE ARTICLES.","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Hair restraint","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not worn on head/hair","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Provide hat or hair net."},{"violationCode":"4-602.13","violationDescription":"NonFOOD-CONTACT SURFACES of EQUIPMENT shall be cleaned at a frequency necessary to preclude accumulation of soil residues.\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Nonfood contact surface(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Soiled","subProblem":"","location":"THROUGHOUT FACILITY","subLocation":"NON FOOD CONTACT SURFACES","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Clean."}]},{"inspectionid":"44626","inspectionDate":"2018-12-17T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"violationCode":"7-202.12","violationDescription":"POISONOUS OR TOXIC MATERIALS shall be:    \n(A) Used according to:      \n(1) LAW and this Code,   \n(2) Manufacturer's use directions included in labeling, and, for a pesticide, manufacturer's label instructions that state that use is allowed in a FOOD ESTABLISHMENT, (P)   \n(3) The conditions of certification, if certification is required, for use of the pest control materials, (P) and   \n(4) Additional conditions that may be established by the REGULATORY AUTHORITY; and\n(B) Applied so that:      \n(1) A HAZARD to EMPLOYEES or other PERSONS is not constituted, (P) and   \n(2) Contamination including toxic residues due to drip, drain, fog, splash or spray on FOOD, EQUIPMENT, UTENSILS, LINENS, AND SINGLE-SERVICE AND SINGLE-USE ARTICLES is prevented, and for a RESTRICTED USE PESTICIDE, this is achieved by: (P)      \n(a) Removing the items, (P)   \n(b) Covering the items with impermeable covers, (P) or   \n(c) Taking other appropriate preventive actions, (P) and   \n(d) Cleaning and SANITIZING EQUIPMENT and UTENSILS after the application. (P)  \n(C) A RESTRICTED USE PESTICIDE shall be applied only by an applicator certified as defined in 7 USC 136 Definitions, (e) Certified Applicator, of the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act, or a PERSON under the direct supervision of a certified applicator. (Pf)","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Poisonous/toxic material(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not used according to manufacturer's label instructions","subProblem":"","location":"BASEMENT","subLocation":"","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"2012-01-17T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Use according to manufacturer label directions."},{"violationCode":"6-501.11","violationDescription":"PHYSICAL FACILITIES shall be maintained in good repair.\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Physical facilities","subItem":"ceiling(s)","problemDescription":"In poor repair","subProblem":"","location":"BASEMENT","subLocation":"Ceiling (s)","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":"0001-01-01T00:00:00","correctionDescription":""},{"violationCode":"2-402.11","violationDescription":"FOOD EMPLOYEES shall wear hair restraints such as hats, hair coverings or nets, beard restraints, and clothing that covers body hair, that are designed and worn to effectively keep their hair from contacting exposed FOOD; clean EQUIPMENT, UTENSILS, and LINENS; or unwrapped SINGLE-SERVICE or SINGLE-USE ARTICLES.","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Hair restraint","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not worn on head/hair","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":"2012-01-17T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Provide hat or hair net."},{"violationCode":"4-501.14","violationDescription":"A WAREWASHING machine; the compartments of sinks, basins, or  other receptacles used for washing and rinsing EQUIPMENT, UTENSILS, or raw FOODS, or laundering wiping cloths; and drainboards or other EQUIPMENT used to substitute for drainboards shall be cleaned as required.\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Warewashing equipment","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not cleaned","subProblem":"","location":"THROUGHOUT FACILITY","subLocation":"","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":"0001-01-01T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Clean as required above."},{"violationCode":"6-501.12","violationDescription":"(A) PHYSICAL FACILITIES shall be cleaned as often as necessary to keep them clean.\n(B) Except spill cleanup, cleaning shall be done during periods when the least amount of FOOD is exposed such as after closing. ","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Physical facilities/structures","subItem":"","problemDescription":"With accumulation of debris","subProblem":"","location":"FACILITY","subLocation":"Throughout","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Keep clean."},{"violationCode":"4-602.13","violationDescription":"NonFOOD-CONTACT SURFACES of EQUIPMENT shall be cleaned at a frequency necessary to preclude accumulation of soil residues.\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":null,"subItem":"","problemDescription":null,"subProblem":"","location":"THROUGHOUT FACILITY","subLocation":"NON FOOD CONTACT SURFACES","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":null},{"violationCode":"4-602.13","violationDescription":"NonFOOD-CONTACT SURFACES of EQUIPMENT shall be cleaned at a frequency necessary to preclude accumulation of soil residues.\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Nonfood contact surface(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Soiled","subProblem":"","location":"THROUGHOUT FACILITY","subLocation":"NON FOOD CONTACT SURFACES","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Clean."},{"violationCode":"4-602.12","violationDescription":"(A) The FOOD-CONTACT SURFACES of cooking and baking EQUIPMENT shall be cleaned at least every 24 hours. This section does not apply to hot oil cooking and filtering EQUIPMENT if it is cleaned as specified in Subparagraph 4-602.11(D)(6).   \n(B) The cavities and door seals of microwave ovens shall be cleaned at least every 24 hours by using the manufacturer's recommended cleaning procedure.","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Baking and cooking equipment","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not cleaned","subProblem":"At least every 24 hours","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"Cooking equipment","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Clean as specified above."},{"violationCode":"4-501.11","violationDescription":"EQUIPMENT shall be maintained in a state of repair and condition that meets the requirements of the code.\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Equipment","subItem":"","problemDescription":"In poor repair","subProblem":"","location":"BAR","subLocation":"GLASS CHILLER","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":"0001-01-01T00:00:00","correctionDescription":""}]},{"inspectionid":"42438","inspectionDate":"2018-05-24T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"No","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"violationCode":"3-501.16","violationDescription":"Except during preparation, cooking, or cooling, or when time is used as the public health control POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD) shall be maintained:\n(A)  135ºF or above, except that roasts properly cooked and cooled may be held              at a temperature of 130ºF; or (P)\n(B)   At 41ºF or less (P)\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Cold food item(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Stored above 41 degrees F","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"Next to the Grill","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"0001-01-01T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Discard"},{"violationCode":"3-303.11","violationDescription":"After use as a medium for cooling the exterior surfaces of FOOD, or cooling coils and tubes of EQUIPMENT, ice may not be used as FOOD. (P)\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Ice","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Used as a cooling medium","subProblem":"","location":"BAR","subLocation":"Ice bin","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"0001-01-01T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Cannot be used for food"},{"violationCode":"4-501.110","violationDescription":"(A) The temperature of the wash solution in spray type warewashers that use hot water to SANITIZERS may not be less than:     \n(1) For a stationary rack, single temperature machine, 74°C (165°F);(Pf)   \n(2) For a stationary rack, dual temperature machine, 66°C (150°F); (Pf)   \n(3) For a single tank, conveyor, dual temperature machine, 71°C (160°F);(Pf) or\n(4) For a multitank, conveyor, multitemperature machine, 66°C (150°F).(Pf)  \n(B) The temperature of the wash solution in spray-type warewashers that use chemicals to SANITIZE may not be less than 49°C (120°F). (Pf)","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Dish machine wash solution temperature","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Less than 120 degrees F","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"Dishwasher (low temperature)","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"0001-01-01T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Repair to provide temperature stated above."},{"violationCode":"4-302.14","violationDescription":"A test kit or other device that accurately measures the concentration in mg/L of SANITIZING solutions shall be provided. (Pf)\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Sanitizer test kit","subItem":"chlorine","problemDescription":"Not provided","subProblem":"","location":"FACILITY","subLocation":"Lack of Test strips","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"0001-01-01T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Provide as required"},{"violationCode":"3-302.11","violationDescription":"(A) FOOD shall be protected from cross contamination by:  \n(1) Except as specified in (1)(c) below, separating raw animal FOODS during         storage, preparation, holding, and display from:\n(a) Raw READY-TO-EAT FOOD including other raw animal FOOD such as FISH for sushi or MOLLUSCAN SHELLFISH, or other raw READY-TO-EAT FOOD such as fruits and vegetables,(P) and\n(b) Cooked READY-TO-EAT FOOD; (P)\n(c) Frozen, commercially processed and packaged raw animal FOOD may be          stored or displayed with or above frozen, commercially processed and           packaged, ready-to-eat food.\n(2) Except when combined as ingredients, separating types of raw animal FOODS    from each other such as beef, FISH, lamb, pork, and POULTRY during storage,        preparation, holding, and display by:\n(a) Using separate EQUIPMENT for each type, (P) or\n(b) Arranging each type of FOOD in EQUIPMENT so that cross contamination of one type with another is prevented, (P) and\n(c) Preparing each type of FOOD at different times or in separate areas; (P)\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Food","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not covered","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"Freezer (reach-in)","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Cover."},{"violationCode":"4-903.11","violationDescription":"Cleaned EQUIPMENT and UTENSILS, laundered LINENS, and SINGLE-SERVICE and SINGLE-USE ARTICLES shall be stored in an approved manner and location.\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Single-service/single-use article(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Stored on floor or less than 6 inches above floor","subProblem":"","location":"BASEMENT","subLocation":"","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Store at least 6 inches above the floor."}]},{"inspectionid":"40607","inspectionDate":"2017-10-25T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"Yes","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"violationCode":"5-202.13","violationDescription":"An air gap between the water supply inlet and the flood level rim of the PLUMBING FIXTURE, EQUIPMENT, or nonFOOD EQUIPMENT shall be at least twice the diameter of the water supply inlet and may not be less than 1 inch. (P)\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Air gap","subItem":"between drain line and flood rim of receiving drain","problemDescription":"Less than twice the diameter of supply line","subProblem":"","location":"3 COMPARTMENT SINK AREA","subLocation":"","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"2010-01-25T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Provide air gap that is twice the diameter of the drain line and no less than 1 inch."},{"violationCode":"3-301.11","violationDescription":"(A) To prevent food contamination FOOD EMPLOYEES shall properly wash their      hands.\n(B) FOOD EMPLOYEES may not contact exposed, READY-TO-EAT FOOD with      their bare hands and shall use suitable UTENSILS such as deli tissue,       spatulas, tongs, single-use gloves, or dispensing EQUIPMENT. (P)\n(C) FOOD EMPLOYEES shall minimize bare hand and arm contact with exposed     FOOD that is not in a READY-TO-EAT form. (Pf)\n\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Ready-to-eat food(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Handled with bare hands","subProblem":"","location":"EMPLOYEE(S)","subLocation":"","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"2010-01-25T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Suitable utensils or single-use gloves are to be utilized."},{"violationCode":"3-304.14","violationDescription":"(A)  Cloths that are in use for wiping FOOD spills on TABLEWARE shall be maintained dry and used for no other purpose. \n(B)  Cloths in-use for wiping counters and equipment shall be held between uses in   a chemical sanitizer solution, and laundered daily.\n(C)  Cloths in-use for wiping surfaces in contact with raw animal FOODS shall be      kept separate from cloths used for other purposes.\n(D)  Dry wiping cloths and the chemical sanitizing solutions shall be free of FOOD    debris or visible soil.\n(E)  Containers of chemical sanitizing solutions shall be stored off the floor and         used in a manner that prevents contamination of FOOD, EQUIPMENT, UTENSILS, LINENS, SINGLE-SERVICE, or SINGLE-USE ARTICLES.\n(E)  SINGLE-USE disposable sanitizer wipes shall be used in accordance lable               instructions.\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Wiping cloth(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Stored on","subProblem":"Counter","location":"ESTABLISHMENT","subLocation":"","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":"2010-01-25T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Store wiping cloths completely submersed in sanitizer."},{"violationCode":"3-302.15","violationDescription":"Raw fruits and vegetables shall be thoroughly washed to remove soil and other contaminants before being prepared or served. ","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Raw","subItem":"Vegetables","problemDescription":"Not washed prior to prep, cooking or service","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Wash prior to use."}]},{"inspectionid":"38543","inspectionDate":"2017-04-13T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"No","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"violationCode":"2-301.14","violationDescription":"FOOD EMPLOYEES shall clean their hands and exposed portions of their arms as specified under § 2-301.12 immediately before engaging in FOOD preparation including working with exposed FOOD, clean EQUIPMENT and UTENSILS, and unwrapped SINGLE-SERVICE and SINGLE-USE ARTICLES (P) and:\n(A)     After touching bare human body parts other than clean hands and clean, exposed portions of arms; (P)\n(B)     After using the toilet room; (P)\n(C)     After caring for or handling SERVICE ANIMALS or aquatic animals as specified in ¶ 2-403.11(B); (P).\n(D)     Except as specified in ¶ 2-401.11(B), after coughing, sneezing, using a handkerchief or disposable tissue, using tobacco, eating, or drinking; (P)\n(E)     After handling soiled EQUIPMENT or UTENSILS; (P)\n(F)     During FOOD preparation, as often as necessary to remove soil and contamination and to prevent cross contamination when changing tasks; (P)\n(G)     When switching between working with raw FOOD and working with READY-TO-EAT FOOD; (P)\n(H)     Before donning gloves for working with FOOD; (P) and\n(I)      After engaging in other activities that contaminate the hands. (P)","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Employee(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Did not wash hands","subProblem":"between raw and ready to eat foods","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"Lack of HAND WASHING","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"0001-01-01T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Hands shall be washed with hot water and soap for at least 20 seconds after contamination."},{"violationCode":"3-501.16","violationDescription":"Except during preparation, cooking, or cooling, or when time is used as the public health control POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD) shall be maintained:\n(A)  135ºF or above, except that roasts properly cooked and cooled may be held              at a temperature of 130ºF; or (P)\n(B)   At 41ºF or less (P)\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Cold food item(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Stored above 41 degrees F","subProblem":"","location":"COOLERS THROUGHOUT","subLocation":"IMPROPER COLD HOLDING TEMPERATURES","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"0001-01-01T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Discard"},{"violationCode":"3-501.14","violationDescription":"(A)  Cooked POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD)  shall be cooled:\n         (1)  Within 2 hours, from 135ºF to 70ºF; and (P) \n         (2)  Within 4 hours, from 70ºF to 41ºF or less (P)\n(B)  POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD)  prepared from ingredients at ambient temperature shall be cooled within 4 hours to 41F or less. (P)\n(C)  POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD)  received in compliance with LAWS   allowing a temperature above 41ºF during shipment from the supplier shall be cooled within 4 hours to 41ºF or less. (P)\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Cooked food(s) cooled","subItem":"","problemDescription":"From 70 degrees f to 41 degrees F for more than 4 hours","subProblem":"","location":"WALK-IN COOLER","subLocation":"","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"0001-01-01T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Discard"},{"violationCode":"3-501.14","violationDescription":"(A)  Cooked POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD)  shall be cooled:\n         (1)  Within 2 hours, from 135ºF to 70ºF; and (P) \n         (2)  Within 4 hours, from 70ºF to 41ºF or less (P)\n(B)  POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD)  prepared from ingredients at ambient temperature shall be cooled within 4 hours to 41F or less. (P)\n(C)  POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD)  received in compliance with LAWS   allowing a temperature above 41ºF during shipment from the supplier shall be cooled within 4 hours to 41ºF or less. (P)\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Cooked food(s) cooled","subItem":"","problemDescription":"From 70 degrees f to 41 degrees F for more than 4 hours","subProblem":"","location":"WALK-IN COOLER","subLocation":"IMPROPER COOLING","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"0001-01-01T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Discard"},{"violationCode":"3-501.15","violationDescription":"(A) Cooling shall be accomplished in accordance with the time and temperature criteria specified under § 3-501.14 by using one or more of the following methods based on the type of FOOD being cooled:  \n   (1) Placing the FOOD in shallow pans; (Pf)\n   (2) Separating the FOOD into smaller or thinner portions; (Pf)\n   (3) Using rapid cooling EQUIPMENT; (Pf)\n   (4) Stirring the FOOD in a container placed in an ice water bath; (Pf)\n   (5) Using containers that facilitate heat transfer; (Pf)\n   (6) Adding ice as an ingredient; (Pf) or\n   (7) Other effective methods. (Pf)  \n(B) When placed in cooling or cold holding EQUIPMENT, FOOD containers in which FOOD is being cooled shall be:  \n   (1) Arranged in the EQUIPMENT to provide maximum heat transfer through the       container walls; and\n   (2) Loosely covered, or uncovered if protected from overhead contamination as          specified under Subparagraph 3-305.11(A)(2), during the cooling period to facilitate    heat transfer from the surface of the FOOD.","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Food item(s) cooled","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Improperly","subProblem":"In large container 5 gallon bucket","location":"WALK-IN COOLER","subLocation":"IMPROPER COOLING","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"0001-01-01T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Utilize long, shallow pans."},{"violationCode":"4-602.11","violationDescription":"(A) Equipment FOOD-CONTACT SURFACES and UTENSILS shall be cleaned:     \n  (1) Except as specified in ¶ (B) of this section, before each use with a different   type of raw animal FOOD such as beef, FISH, lamb, pork, or POULTRY; (P)   \n  (2) Each time there is a change from working with raw FOODS to working with   READY-TO-EAT FOODS; (P)   \n  (3) Between uses with raw fruits and vegetables and with POTENTIALLY   HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD);   (P)   \n  (4) Before using or storing a FOOD TEMPERATURE MEASURING   DEVICE; (P) and   \n  (5) At any time during the operation when contamination may have occurred. (P)\n(B) Subparagraph (A)(1) of this section does not apply if the FOOD-CONTACT SURFACE or UTENSIL is in contact with a succession of different raw animal FOODS each requiring a higher cooking temperature as specified under § 3-401.11 than the previous FOOD, such as preparing raw FISH followed by cutting raw poultry on the same cutting board.   \n(C) Except as specified in ¶ (D) of this section, if used with POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD), EQUIPMENT FOOD-CONTACT SURFACES and UTENSILS shall be cleaned throughout the day at least every 4 hours. (P)   \n(D) Except when dry cleaning methods are used as specified under § 4-603.11, surfaces of UTENSILS and EQUIPMENT contacting FOOD that is not POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD) shall be cleaned:     \n  (1)   At any time when contamination may have occurred;\n  (2)   At least every 24 hours for iced tea dispensers and CONSUMER self-service UTENSILS such as tongs, scoops, or ladles;\n  (3) Before restocking CONSUMER self-service EQUIPMENT and UTENSILS such as condiment dispensers and display containers; and\n  (4) In EQUIPMENT such as ice bins and BEVERAGE dispensing nozzles and   enclosed components of EQUIPMENT such as ice makers, cooking oil storage   tanks and distribution lines, BEVERAGE and syrup dispensing lines or tubes,   coffee bean grinders, and water vending EQUIPMENT:\n     (a) At a frequency specified by the manufacturer, or\n     (b) Absent manufacturer specifications, at a frequency necessary to preclude      accumulation of soil or mold.","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Food-contact surface(s) used for nonpotentially hazardous food(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not cleaned","subProblem":"At least every 24 hours","location":"BAR","subLocation":"","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"2010-01-25T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Clean as specified above."},{"violationCode":"4-602.13","violationDescription":"NonFOOD-CONTACT SURFACES of EQUIPMENT shall be cleaned at a frequency necessary to preclude accumulation of soil residues.\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Nonfood contact surface(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Soiled","subProblem":"","location":"THROUGHOUT FACILITY","subLocation":"NON FOOD CONTACT SURFACES","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":"2010-01-25T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Clean."},{"violationCode":"6-501.12","violationDescription":"(A) PHYSICAL FACILITIES shall be cleaned as often as necessary to keep them clean.\n(B) Except spill cleanup, cleaning shall be done during periods when the least amount of FOOD is exposed such as after closing. ","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Physical facilities/structures","subItem":"","problemDescription":"With accumulation of debris","subProblem":"","location":"FACILITY","subLocation":"Throughout","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":"2010-01-25T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Keep clean."},{"violationCode":"4-501.14","violationDescription":"A WAREWASHING machine; the compartments of sinks, basins, or  other receptacles used for washing and rinsing EQUIPMENT, UTENSILS, or raw FOODS, or laundering wiping cloths; and drainboards or other EQUIPMENT used to substitute for drainboards shall be cleaned as required.\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Warewashing equipment","subItem":"three compartment sink basins","problemDescription":"Not cleaned","subProblem":"Before use","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"Three compartment sink","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":"2010-01-25T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Clean as specified above."},{"violationCode":"4-501.14","violationDescription":"A WAREWASHING machine; the compartments of sinks, basins, or  other receptacles used for washing and rinsing EQUIPMENT, UTENSILS, or raw FOODS, or laundering wiping cloths; and drainboards or other EQUIPMENT used to substitute for drainboards shall be cleaned as required.\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Warewashing equipment","subItem":"three compartment sink basins","problemDescription":"Not cleaned","subProblem":"Through out the day as necessary","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"IMPROPER Three compartment sink","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":"2010-01-25T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Clean as specified above."},{"violationCode":"6-501.18","violationDescription":"PLUMBING FIXTURES such as HANDWASHING SINKS, toilets, and urinals shall be cleaned as often as necessary to keep them clean. \n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Handwashing facility","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Soiled","subProblem":"","location":"FACILITY","subLocation":"Throughout Hand sink(s)","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":"2010-01-25T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Keep clean."},{"violationCode":"MFL289.2129","violationDescription":"Sec. 2129. (1) All food establishments shall employ a minimum of 1 managerial employee as a food safety manager, who must be an individual who is currently certified under a personnel certification program accredited by the American National Standards Institute, utilizing the Conference for Food Protection standards:\n(2) Beginning January 14, 2017 and every 5 years thereafter, a certified  food safety manager who supervises the operations of a food service establishment shall have completed a food safety training program\ncontaining an allergen awareness  component that has been approved by  the department. A food service establishment shall retain records on the  site of the food service establishment documenting compliance of its  certified food safety managers with this subsection. ","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Person-in-charge","subItem":"","problemDescription":null,"subProblem":"","location":"PERSON IN CHARGE","subLocation":"","corrected":"False","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":null,"correctionDescription":"Provide."}]},{"inspectionid":"37151","inspectionDate":"2016-09-13T00:00:00","inspectionType":"Routine Inspection","inCompliance":"No","violationsByInspectionidList":[{"violationCode":"3-501.14","violationDescription":"(A)  Cooked POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD)  shall be cooled:\n         (1)  Within 2 hours, from 135ºF to 70ºF; and (P) \n         (2)  Within 4 hours, from 70ºF to 41ºF or less (P)\n(B)  POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD)  prepared from ingredients at ambient temperature shall be cooled within 4 hours to 41F or less. (P)\n(C)  POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD)  received in compliance with LAWS   allowing a temperature above 41ºF during shipment from the supplier shall be cooled within 4 hours to 41ºF or less. (P)\n","violationType":"Priority","itemDescription":"Cooked food(s) cooled","subItem":"","problemDescription":"From 135 degrees f to 70 degrees F for more than 2 hours","subProblem":"","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"IMPROPER Food Storage","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"0001-01-01T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Utilize shallow pans, ice baths, agitation, or quick chilling to cool food items."},{"violationCode":"4-302.14","violationDescription":"A test kit or other device that accurately measures the concentration in mg/L of SANITIZING solutions shall be provided. (Pf)\n","violationType":"Foundation","itemDescription":"Sanitizer test kit","subItem":"chlorine","problemDescription":"Not provided","subProblem":"","location":"FACILITY","subLocation":"Lack of Test strips","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"0001-01-01T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Provide as required"},{"violationCode":"3-305.14","violationDescription":"During preparation, unPACKAGED FOOD shall be protected from environmental sources of contamination.\n","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Unpackaged food(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not protected","subProblem":"From contamination","location":"KITCHEN","subLocation":"In the Cooler (top loader)","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"30","correctedDate":"0001-01-01T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Store in protected manner."},{"violationCode":"4-602.11","violationDescription":"(A) Equipment FOOD-CONTACT SURFACES and UTENSILS shall be cleaned:     \n  (1) Except as specified in ¶ (B) of this section, before each use with a different   type of raw animal FOOD such as beef, FISH, lamb, pork, or POULTRY; (P)   \n  (2) Each time there is a change from working with raw FOODS to working with   READY-TO-EAT FOODS; (P)   \n  (3) Between uses with raw fruits and vegetables and with POTENTIALLY   HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD);   (P)   \n  (4) Before using or storing a FOOD TEMPERATURE MEASURING   DEVICE; (P) and   \n  (5) At any time during the operation when contamination may have occurred. (P)\n(B) Subparagraph (A)(1) of this section does not apply if the FOOD-CONTACT SURFACE or UTENSIL is in contact with a succession of different raw animal FOODS each requiring a higher cooking temperature as specified under § 3-401.11 than the previous FOOD, such as preparing raw FISH followed by cutting raw poultry on the same cutting board.   \n(C) Except as specified in ¶ (D) of this section, if used with POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS FOOD (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD), EQUIPMENT FOOD-CONTACT SURFACES and UTENSILS shall be cleaned throughout the day at least every 4 hours. (P)   \n(D) Except when dry cleaning methods are used as specified under § 4-603.11, surfaces of UTENSILS and EQUIPMENT contacting FOOD that is not POTENTIALLY HAZARDOUS (TIME/TEMPERATURE CONTROL FOR SAFETY FOOD) shall be cleaned:     \n  (1)   At any time when contamination may have occurred;\n  (2)   At least every 24 hours for iced tea dispensers and CONSUMER self-service UTENSILS such as tongs, scoops, or ladles;\n  (3) Before restocking CONSUMER self-service EQUIPMENT and UTENSILS such as condiment dispensers and display containers; and\n  (4) In EQUIPMENT such as ice bins and BEVERAGE dispensing nozzles and   enclosed components of EQUIPMENT such as ice makers, cooking oil storage   tanks and distribution lines, BEVERAGE and syrup dispensing lines or tubes,   coffee bean grinders, and water vending EQUIPMENT:\n     (a) At a frequency specified by the manufacturer, or\n     (b) Absent manufacturer specifications, at a frequency necessary to preclude      accumulation of soil or mold.","violationType":"Core","itemDescription":"Food-contact surface(s) used for nonpotentially hazardous food(s)","subItem":"","problemDescription":"Not cleaned","subProblem":"","location":"ICE MACHINE","subLocation":"","corrected":"True","daysToCorrect":"10","correctedDate":"0001-01-01T00:00:00","correctionDescription":"Clean as required above."}]}]}],"maxInspectionDate":[{"inspectionDate":"2023-04-13T00:00:00"}]}},"pageContext":{"eid":"2140"}},"staticQueryHashes":["3649515864","63159454"]}